plantation owners went to Germany to find out how they could control our fathers and
mothers on the plantation, but they were getting out of hand. They were burning the houses
down. They were killing white folk. They were doing everything negative about being in captivity.
They were never slaves. They were prisoners of war, the war of 1591. So what happened
was, they sought the advice of an expert in Songhai history. Now, his name was Johann Blumenbach,
and he was the head of the Department of History at the University of Göttingen in Germany.
Well, when they sought his advice, they said, do they know that they're the Songhai people?
So the plantation owners who traveled over there to seek his advice said, well, of course
they know that they come from the great Songhai empire. Well, that's your problem. You can't
let them know that they came from greatness, from grandeur, from beauty, from sophistication.
You'll never be able to control them. Well, how do you want to stop it? Here's how you do
it. Here's why you don't know where you're from. What you do, as soon as a boatload arrives,
take the babies out of Mama's arms, send the parents to a distant plantation and work them
to death, and raise the children to believe they came from a jungle. They won't know the
difference. That's right. How would they know? That's right. Their parents are gone.